ABDALLAH SIDDIG OSMAN HUSSEIN

IT Technical Support and Network engineer

Address: Ras Al Khaimah, United Arab Emirates

D.O.B: September 5th,1996

Nationality: Sudan

E-mail: abdosiddig12@gmail.com

Mobile: +971-52-3467504

CAREER OBJECTIVE

A Network and Technical Support Engineer with 2 years of experience in IT including computer & networks installation. Have a strong knowledge in communication, customer services, and administrative skills. A very good understanding and knowledge of Network administrator, Technical Support, Network and hardware maintenance, repair and troubleshooting.

Seeking for a technical support position as well as to be a part of a successful working team, where I can learn more & educate on what I have learned.

WORK EXPERIENCE

May 2018 – Jan 2020

Network and Technical Support Engineer

ALFAFA For Computer Co. Ltd, Sudan.

- Planning, designing and implementation of computer networks.
- Building, installing, configuring, upgrading, maintenance and repair Microsoft windows servers, Cisco Routers, Switches, Firewalls, Wireless devices, CCTV systems, Fingerprint and Access control systems.
- Technical support of end-users.
- Provide technical support, troubleshooting and repair of windows systems, PCs, Printer, Scanners Fax machines and Photocopiers.

April 2017 – April 2018

GIS Analyst(as National Service)

TPRA (Telecommunication and Postal Regulation Authority), Sudan.

December 2016 – January 2017

Call Center Agent

Sudani Telecom Company, Sudan.

- Answer phone calls courteously and actively listen to the customer to determine questions or needs, then verify customer information and provide excellent customer service.
- Follow company protocol and scripts to answer customer questions and provide product information, continually learning new product descriptions and participating in training opportunities to improve skills.
- Calling and Monitoring Points of Sell.

August 2015 – September 2015

Trainee Technical Support Engineer

Bank of Al Baraka, Sudan.

- Technical support of end-users.
- Provide technical support, troubleshooting and repair of windows systems, PCs, Printer, Scanners Fax machines and Photocopiers.

EDUCATION

September 2012 – June 2016

Bachelor of Science in Information & Communication Technology

University of Science & Technology, Sudan.

QUALIFICATIONS

December 2017 – January 2018

CCNA Training Course at SUDACAD Training Center, Sudan.

Cisco Certified Network Associate, Routing and Switching.

Key Skills:

SKILLS

- Installing, configuring, upgrading, and troubleshooting of computer hardware and software.
- Planning and implementation of computer networks.
- Excellent knowledge of computer architecture, PCs troubleshooting, data communication, Computer networks wire/wireless communication and all Microsoft Office products including MS-Project.

Hardware/Software:

Installing operating systems, maintenance of computer (hardware and software), connecting and maintain networks and provide technical support to users.

Applications:

Microsoft office suite: word, excel, outlook and power point.

Soft Skills:

- Customer service skills
- Verbal communication skills
- Written communication skills
- Ability prioritize and multitask
- Problem-solving skills
- Competence in office software
- Relationship management
- Rapport-building

Key Competencies:

- Information Technologies and Network Management.
- Technical Support and Troubleshooting. Hardware/Software (All Windows Systems, Servers, Routers, Switches, PCs, Printers, Scanner, Fax, Photocopier).
- Professionally competent & committed employee.
- Able to establish supportive relationships within a team.
- Organized, hardworking & quick learner.
- Friendly with excellent presentation skills.

LANGUAGES

Arabic: Native language.

English: Good reading, writing and speaking.

REFERENCES

- Mr. Moyasar Mohamed Almagboul Abdallah

Network Engineer at Alfafa For Computer Co.Ltd

Primary Contact Information:

Phone No: +249915730822

E-mail: moyasar.mohamed@gmail.com

- Mr. Dafallah Mohamed Ahmed

GIS Analyst at National Telecommunication Corporation.

Primary Contact Information: Phone No: +249910111990

E-mail: dafaalla.mohamed@tpra.gov.sd